Jiachen Li

Etcheverry Hall, Berkeley, CA 94709, USA

Personal Website

in LinkedIn

G Google Scholar

☑ jiachen_li@berkeley.edu

Research Interests

My research interest lies in the intersection of machine learning, optimization, computer vision approaches and their applications to relational reasoning, state estimation, behavior prediction, decision making and motion planning for multi-agent intelligent systems such as autonomous vehicles and robots.

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering (Robotics) Academic advisor: Prof. Masayoshi Tomizuka

Specialization: machine learning, graph neural network, prediction, tracking, planning

Harbin Institute of Technology

B. Eng. in Automation (Honors School)

Academic advisors: Prof. Huijun Gao and Prof. Shen Yin

Thesis: Partial Least Squares and Its Application to Process Control

Berkeley, CA, USA 08/2016 - Present

Harbin, China

Berkeley, CA, USA

08/2016 - Present

Harbin, China

03/2014 - 06/2016

08/2012 - 07/2016

Research Experience

University of California, Berkeley

Graduate Student Researcher

Mechanical Systems Control (MSC) Laboratory & Berkeley DeepDrive (BDD)

Research Assistant Research Institute of Intelligent Control and System

Harbin Institute of Technology

Industry Experience

Honda Research Institute

Research Intern

Machine Learning and Computer Vision, Scene Understanding

Toyota Research Institute

Research Intern

Machine Learning and Planning Teams, Behavior Prediction

San Jose, CA, USA

09/2019 - Present

Los Altos, CA, USA

06/2019 - 08/2019

Journal Publications

- o J. Li, H. Ma, Z. Zhang, J. Li and M. Tomizuka, "Spatio-Temporal Graph Dual-Attention Network for Multi-Agent Prediction and Tracking", submitted to IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems, under review.
- o H. Ma*, Y. Sun*, J. Li, L. Rong and M. Tomizuka, "CIA-TP: Continual Interaction-Aware Trajectory Prediction across Different Scenarios", submitted to IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems, under review.
- o C. Gong, X. Zhou, Z. Li, J. Li, J. Li, J. Cong, J. Zhou, "Orientation-Aware Planning for Parallel Task Execution of Omni-Directional Mobile Robot", submitted to IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters, under review.
- o J. Li, W. Zhan, Y. Hu and M. Tomizuka, "Generic Tracking and Prediction Framework and Its Application in Autonomous Driving", IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems, 21(9), 3634-3649, 2020.

- o J. Li, C. Duan and Z. Fei, "A Novel Variable Selection Approach for Redundant Information Elimination Purpose of Process Control", *IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics*, 63(3), 1737-1744, 2016.
- o C. Duan, Z. Fei and J. Li, "A Variable Selection Aided Residual Generator Design Approach for Process Control and Monitoring", *Neurocomputing*, 171, 1013-1020, 2016.
- o S. Shi, Z. Fei and **J. Li**, "Finite-time Hinf Control of Switched Systems with Mode-dependent Average Dwell Time", *Journal of the Franklin Institute*, 353(1), 221-234, 2016.

Conference Publications

- o J. Li*, F. Yang*, M. Tomizuka and C. Choi, "EvolveGraph: Multi-Agent Trajectory Prediction with Dynamic Relational Reasoning", in Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2020.
- J. Li, F. Yang, H. Ma, S. Malla, M. Tomizuka and C. Choi, "RAIN: Reinforced Hybrid Attention Inference Network for Motion Forecasting", under review.
- o X. Ma, **J. Li**, M. J. Kochenderfer, D. Isele and K. Fujimura, "Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Driving with Latent State Inference and Spatial-Temporal Relationships", submitted to *ICRA2021*, under review.
- D. Cao*, J. Li, H. Ma and M. Tomizuka, "Spectral Temporal Graph Neural Network for Trajectory Prediction", submitted to ICRA2021, under review.
- o J. Li, H. Ma, Z. Zhang and M. Tomizuka, "A²-GNN: Interaction-Aware Trajectory Prediction via Graph Double-Attention Network", RSS Workshop on Interaction and Decision-Making in Autonomous Driving, 2020.
- J. Li, H. Ma, and M. Tomizuka, "Conditional Generative Neural System for Probabilistic Trajectory Prediction", in 2019 IEEE Conference on Robotics and Systems (IROS), 2019.
- J. Li*, H. Ma* and M. Tomizuka, "Interaction-aware Multi-agent Tracking and Probabilistic Behavior Prediction via Adversarial Learning", in 2019 IEEE Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2019.
- o **J. Li**, H. Ma, W. Zhan and M. Tomizuka, "Coordination and Trajectory Prediction for Vehicle Interactions via Bayesian Generative Modeling", in *2019 IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV)*, 2019.
- H. Ma, J. Li, W. Zhan and M. Tomizuka, "Wasserstein Generative Learning with Kinematic Constraints for Probabilistic Interactive Driving Behavior Prediction", in 2019 IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV), 2019.
- J. Li, H. Ma, W. Zhan and M. Tomizuka, "Generic Probabilistic Interactive Situation Recognition and Prediction: From Virtual to Real", in 2018 IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC), 2018.
- o J. Li, W. Zhan and M. Tomizuka, "Generic Vehicle Tracking Framework Capable of Handling Occlusions Based on Modified Mixture Particle Filter", in 2018 IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV)(oral), 936-942, 2018.
- o W. Zhan, L. Sun, Y. Hu, **J. Li** and M. Tomizuka, "Towards a Fatality-Aware Benchmark of Probabilistic Reaction Prediction in Highly Interactive Driving Scenarios", in 2018 IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC), 2018.
- W. Zhan, J. Li, Y. Hu and M. Tomizuka, "Safe and Feasible Motion Generation for Autonomous Driving via Constrained Policy Net", in *Industrial Electronics Society, IECON 2017-43rd Annual Conference of the IEEE*, 4588-4593, 2017.

Patent Applications

- J. Li and C. Choi, "System and Method for Motion Forecasting with Reinforced Hybrid Attention Inference Network", application in process.
- J. Li and C. Choi, "System and Method for Trajectory Prediction with Evolving Interaction Graphs", application in process.
- X. Ma, J. Li, M. J. Kochenderfer, D. Isele and K. Fujimura, "System and Method of Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Driving with Latent State Inference and Spatial-Temporal Relationships", application in process.
- B. Wulfe, J. Ge and J. Li, "Systems and Methods for Hybrid Prediction Framework with Inductive Bias", application in process.

Awards and Honors

 Top Reviewer for ICML 2020 Top Ten Outstanding Graduate at Harbin Institute of Technology 	2020 2016
o Chunhui Innovation Fellowship (Top 1%)	2016
o Suzhou Industry Fellowship	2015
o Meritorious Winner, Mathematical/Interdisciplinary Contest in Modeling	2015
o China Renmin Scholarship	2013, 2014, 2015, 2016
Invited Talks and Oral Presentations	
o A^2 -GNN: Interaction-Aware Trajectory Prediction, RSS Workshop	07/2020
o Conditional Generative Neural System for Trajectory Prediction, IROS	11/2019
o Incorporating Relational Reasoning in Multi-agent Trajectory Prediction, IROS Worksh	юр 11/2019
o Inductive Bias in Behavior Prediction Models, Carnegie Mellon University	08/2019
o Generative Models for Probabilistic Trajectory Prediction, IV Workshop	06/2019
 Probabilistic Interactive Situation Recognition and Prediction, ITSC 	11/2018
o Generic Vehicle Tracking Framework Capable of Handling Occlusions, IV	06/2018
Journal Reviewer	
o IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (T-PAMI)	2020 – Present
o IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics (T-IE)	2017 – Present
 IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems (T-ITS) 	2017 – Present
o IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Vehicles (T-IV)	2018 – Present
 IEEE Transactions on Mechatronics (T-MECH) 	2019 – Present
o IEEE Transactions on Robotics (T-RO)	2020 – Present
Neural Computing and Applications (NCAA)	2020 – Present
Conference Reviewer	
o Adcances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)	2020
 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 	2020
 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 	2019, 2020
 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 	2019, 2020
o IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV)	2019, 2020
o IEEE Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC)	2019, 2020
Program Committee	
o Associate Editor of IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IV)	2020
o Co-organizer of Workshops at IEEE Intelligent Vehicle Symposium (IV)	2019, 2020
Computer Skills	

Computer Skills

- **Programming**: Python, C & C++, MATLAB/Simulink
- o **Deep Learning Framework**: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Caffe
- Design and Simulation: ROS, Multisim, AutoCAD, OrCAD